{"tossups": [{"question": "This man, the last foreign head of state to serve in U.S. Congress, was shot in the ankle while leading troops with the battle cry \u201cRemember Goliad!\u201d This winning general at the 18-minute-long Battle of San Jacinto refused loyalty to the Confederacy after the secession of his home state. For the point, name this two-time President of the Republic of Texas, the namesake of the most populous city in Texas.", "answer": "Sam<b> Houston</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This author compared the \u201cMental Lives of Savages and Neurotics\u201d in one work. He fled from the Nazis after his daughter, the author of<em> The Ego and Mechanisms of Defense</em>, was interrogated by the Gestapo. This author of<em> Civilization and its Discontents</em> developed a model of the psyche as id, ego, and super-ego. For the point, name this Austrian psychologist, the author of<em> The Interpretation of Dreams</em>.", "answer": "Sigmund<b> Freud</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This leader supported the killings of the Acholi and Lango ethnic groups at the Jinja barracks. In 1972, this leader expropriated Indian-owned property by forcing his country\u2019s 80,000 Asian residents to leave. This self-proclaimed \u201cConqueror of the British Empire\u201d also gave himself the title \u201cLord of all the Beasts of the Earth and Fishes of the Seas\u201d shortly after overthrowing Milton Obote and taking power in Kampala. For the point, name this former dictator of Uganda.", "answer": "Idi<b> Amin</b> Dada", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This ruler had his wife, Fausta, killed by leaving her in an overheated bath. He won a battle to come to power after having a vision of a labarum accompanied by the words \u201cin this sign, you will conquer.\u201dAt that battle, this ruler allied with a future rival, Licinius, to defeat Maxentius at the Milvian Bridge to take control of Rome. For the point, name this first Roman emperor to convert to Christianity.", "answer": "<b> Constantine I</b> or<b> Constantine the Great</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "In the second century AD, Hua Tuo created a mixture known as \u201cmafeisan\u201d to serve this purpose. George Harley pioneered the use of ACE mixture for this task, but in the 20th century, the C in ACE, chloroform, stopped being used for this task due to associated cardiac complications. Diethyl ether and nitrous oxide can be used to accomplish this purpose through inhalation. For the point, name this temporary, medically induced state in which a patient is unable to feel pain during surgery.", "answer": "general<b> anesthesia</b> (accept any word form, like<b> anesthetic</b>; prompt on \u201c(medically induced) coma;\u201d prompt on \u201c(medically induced\u201d unconsciousness)", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {"question": "Mikhail Yegorov and Meliton Kantaria were said to have stood on this building in 1945. Its 1990s renovation was designed by Norman Foster, who built a large glass dome atop it. Communists were blamed for a fire that burned this building in 1933; in reaction, Paul von Hindenburg decreed the imprisonment of opponents of the Nazis. The Bundestag meets in, for the point, what building that houses the German Parliament?", "answer": "<b> Reichstag</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "Cassander named himself King of this empire in 302 BC as part of the short-lived Antipatrid dynasty, which was overthrown by Antigonus. This empire\u2019s 338 BC victory at Chaeronea allowed it to ally the Greek city-states against Darius III. Pausanias assassinated this empire\u2019s ruler before the beginning of that war against Persia, which was decided at Gaugamela. For the point, name this ancient kingdom ruled by Philip II and Alexander the Great.", "answer": "<b> Macedon</b>ia Page 2", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man called Mitch McConnell an \u201cenormous obstacle\u201d for his initial failure to renew the Zadroga Act, which funded health care for 9/11 first responders. To direct the 2014 film<em> Rosewater</em>, this man took a hiatus during which John Oliver replaced him; after his 2015 retirement, he was replaced by Trevor Noah. For the point, name this former Comedy Central host of<em> The Daily Show</em>.", "answer": "Jon<b> Stewart</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "This ruler conquered the forces of King Nabonidus, who is disparaged by a cylinder describing this man\u2019s plan for restoring Babylon. After defeating Astyages [uh-STY-uh-geez] and capturing Ecbatana, this man defeated Croesus [KREE-sus] of Lydia. This man built a new city, Pasargadae [pah-SAR-ga-DEE], as the capital of his new empire. For the point, name this \u201cgreat\u201d founder of the Achaemenid [uh-KEE-meh-nid] Empire in Persia.", "answer": "<b> Cyrus the Great</b> or<b> Cyrus II</b> of Persia or<b> Cyrus the Elder</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "One of these places was placed on land owned by Robert E. Lee\u2019s wife that was confiscated by the government in 1864. Edward Everett spoke for two hours at the dedication of another of these locations, which another man claimed \u201cwe can not consecrate\u201d in an address that opened \u201cFour score and seven years ago\u201d. For the point, name these locations, like the former battlefield of Gettysburg and Arlington, where American soldiers are buried.", "answer": "national military<b> cemetery</b> (accept additional information mentioning the U.S. Civil War)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In one of this author\u2019s short stories, Robert Wilson watches a man shoot a buffalo as Margot shoots that man in the head. In a novel by this author of \u201cThe Short Happy Life of Francis Macomber,\u201d Pablo helps Robert Jordan blow up a bridge during the Spanish Civil War. This man wrote a novel based on his experience as an ambulance driver in World War I in which Catherine Barkley has an affair with Frederic Henry. For the point, name this American author of<em> For Whom the Bell Tolls</em> and<em> The Sun Also Rises</em>.", "answer": "Ernest Miller<b> Hemingway</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "The wife of Spartacus was an initiate into a cult worshipping this god. In the second century AD, Herodes Atticus built an odeon next to a theater honoring this god on the Acropolis. This son of Semele gained the epithet \u201ctwice-born,\u201d as he was actually born through Zeus\u2019 thigh. Bacchus was an alternative name of, for the point, what Greek god of fertility and wine?", "answer": "<b> Dionysus</b> (or<b> Bacchus</b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "Adolphe Thiers [t\u2019yair] built a wall around this city in the 19th century. Its namesake university was founded in 1150 and is sometimes called the Sorbonne. This city\u2019s oldest bridge was built under a ruler who said this city was \u201cwell worth a mass\u201d after converting to Catholicism. The Pont Neuf crosses the Ile de la Cit\u00b4e over the Seine River in, for the point, what capital of France?", "answer": "<b> Paris</b> Page 4", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A 1669 eruption on this island was diverted from the city of Catania by that city\u2019s walls. Settlers from Corinth founded another city on this island where Archimedes was killed. This island is separated from Calabria by the Strait of Messina, and this island contains the tallest active volcano in Europe, Mount Etna. Syracuse is found on, for the point, what triangular Mediterranean island off the boot of Italy?", "answer": "<b> Sicily</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This city is supplied by the \u201cBig Allis\u201d natural gas generator, which shut down after lightning strikes in Buchanan. The Rockaways were unaffected by that problem, which came while the \u201cSon of Sam\u201dterrorized this city, because they were covered not by Consolidated Edison, but the Long Island Lighting Company. For the point, name this city where a 1977 blackout struck all but the borough of Queens, leading to rampant looting in the Bronx.", "answer": "<b> New York</b> City", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This ship inspired Karl Goetz to design a medal with a skeleton and the German phrase \u201cBusiness Above All.\u201d William Thomas Turner\u2019s failure to zigzag near the Old Head of Kinsale may have helped lead to this ship\u2019s fate, which was sealed when<em> U-20</em>, a German submarine, fired one torpedo. An explosion of contraband ammunition sped the 1915 sinking of, for the point, what British ocean liner, whose sinking helped convince the U.S. to join World War I?", "answer": "RMS<b> Lusitania</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Supreme Court ruled that this amendment protects corporate donations to political campaigns in the<em> Citizens United</em> case. Prior restraint almost always violates this amendment, as when President Nixon tried to use it to stop the<em> New York Times</em> from publishing the Pentagon Papers. For the point, name this Constitutional amendment that protects the freedoms of petition, assembly, press, religion, and speech.", "answer": "<b> 1</b>st Amendment to the U.S. Constitution <b>Extra Question</b> Page 5", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The North West Company and the Hudson\u2019s Bay Company\u2019s trading posts along this body of water included Fort William and Grand Portage, both gateways to western Canada. A 1975 storm on this body of water led to the sinking of the<em> SS Edmund Fitzgerald</em>. The two largest cities on this body of water are Thunder Bay, Ontario, and Duluth, Minnesota. For the point, name this largest of the Great Lakes.", "answer": "Lake<b> Superior</b> Page 6", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}], "bonuses": []}